# **Daehwa Kim**

291, Daehak-ro, Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, Republic of Korea daehwakim@kaist.ac.kr • +82 6860 8558 • https://daehwa.github.io

#### RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research goal is engineering for a fluid interface, exploring a seamless integration of a computer and human that makes new and pleasant experiences. My prior research lies in (a) novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs and (b) sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device. I published full papers at ACM CHI and UIST.

# Research Interests Sensing Techniques for Fluid Interfaces novel sensing technologies supporting sophisticated hand inputs - AtaTouch (To Appear CHI'21) + OddEyeCam (UIST'20) - MagTouch (CHI'20) novel sensing technologies supporting sensing and interaction techniques for a mobile device - OddEyeCam (UIST'20) - OmniSense (Ongoing)

#### **EDUCATION**

# KAIST, Human-Computer Interaction Lab

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- M.S. in School of Computing
  - Adviser: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
  - Focus: Sensing Techniques
  - Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" (2020 Best Thesis Award)
     Thesis Committee: Geehyuk Lee (Chair), Juho Kim, Uichin Lee

## **UNIST**, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Mar 2015 – Feb 2019

- B.S. in Computer Science and Engineering (Major)
- B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Minor)
- Thesis: "VRone: 3D Force Feedback System in VR Using a Commercial Drone"
- Entered with top honors.
- Graduated with Magna Cum Laude
- Summer session program, ual: (University of the Arts London), London, UK

Jul 2018

## **PUBLICATIONS**

# **CONFERENCES**

- [1] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" To Appear in *Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Yokohama, Japan. (full paper, To Appear) Honorable Mention Award
- [2] <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" in *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*, Virtual Event, USA, Oct 2020. (full paper)
- [3] Keunwoo Park, <u>Daehwa Kim</u>, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee, "MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer" in *Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*, Honolulu, Hawaii, USA, Apr 2020. (full paper)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

# HCI Lab, KAIST

Undergraduate Research Student, School of Computing

Mar 2018 - Jun 2018

- Project: PCB design for a hand gesture sensing wristband.
- Supervisors: Prof. Geehyuk Lee
- Focus: human-computer interaction, PCB design, physical prototyping

#### Hyper-connected Communication Research Laboratory, ETRI

Research Intern, IoT Research Division

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

- Project: Smart Home project Building IoT lighting system controlled by user's voice
- · Supervisors: Dr Jungsik Sung and Daeho Kim
- Focus: IoT network system, Natural language processing

# iHCI Lab (Intelligent Human Computer Interaction Lab), UNIST

· Project: Finger Joystick Interaction • Supervisors: Prof. Sungahn Ko • Focus: human-computer interaction, capacitive sensing, visualization **AWARDS &** Honorable Mention Award, ACM CHI 2021 Mar 2021 **SCHOLARSHIPS** ■ Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee, "AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss" To Appear in Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, Yokohama, Japan. Best Master's Thesis Award, KAIST School of Computing Feb 2021 Thesis: "OddEyeCam: Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction Using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras" Dec 2017 **4th Prize**, NAVER x UNIST Undergraduate Poster Award • Topic: "VibCat: Vibration Categorization for Input and Interaction". Awarded by NAVER CEO. • Received an award of 1,000,000 KRW. **Excellence Award**, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016 Dec 2016 Dispatched to Uzbekistan to provide Android development lectures to university students. Awarded by the Director of National Information Society Agency. • Received an award of Samsung Galaxy Tab 4 10.1. Dean's List, UNIST 2017 Fall Dean's List: GPA 4.05/4.3 Jan 2018 2017 Spring Dean's List: GPA 3.98/4.3 Jul 2017 2016 Fall Dean's List: GPA 3.90/4.3 Feb 2016 ■ 2016 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.06/4.3 Aug 2016 2015 Spring Dean's List: GPA 4.00/4.3 Jul 2015 Uni-Star Scholarship, UNIST Mar 2015 - Feb 2019 • Entered with top honors. ■ Tuition + academic support fee of 1,000,000 KRW were paid each semester. Overseas Training Scholarship, UNIST Jun 2018 • Financial aid for the summer session program at University of the Arts London **TEACHING** Teaching Assistant, AI Lab - Learning Commons II, UNIST Sep 2018 – Dec 2018 **EXPERIENCE** Head of Android Developement Team, HeXA, UNIST Feb 2017 - Dec 2017 **Instructor**, Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT) Jul 2016 - Sep 2016 • Excellence Award, World Friends ICT volunteers return report 2016 **ACADEMIC** Reviewer **SERVICE** ■ CHI '21 LBW **CAMPUS** D2 factory, NAVER **ACTIVITIES**  Campus Partner Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 • Hosted the 2nd Hackathon at UNIST, sponsored by NAVER and UNIST ECE HeXA (Hacker's eXciting Academy), UNIST A computer security & development research group ■ Vice-President Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 Feb 2017 - Dec 2017 Head of Android development team • Provided regular anndroid-development lectures for club members UNIST Media Center, UNIST Video Editor Mar 2015 – Feb 2017 ■ Representative work • My Age 22 - Travel to Europe with a drone • Web drama: The town where engineers live **PROJECTS Audio Hero** Sep 2019 – Dec 2019 Sound-based danger detection system using VGGish deep learning model

Undergraduate Research Student, Electrical and Computer Engineering

Feb 2017 - Nov 2017

• Skills: Deep learning, Signal processing

**VRone** Sep 2018 – Dec 2018

3-dimensional force feedback in VR using a personal and commercial drone

• Skills: Unity C# programming, Android programming

System Light 2.0 @ ETRI

Jan 2018 – Mar 2018

Smart Home project - Building IoT system for lights

• Skills: Computer network, Natural language processing

**VibCat** Oct 2017 – Dec 2017

■ Vibration Categorization for Input & Interaction

• Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

# Finger joystick interaction

Feb 2017 – Nov 2017

• Interaction technique to support finger's directional input using capacitive image of a smartwatch's touchscreen

• Skills: Machine learning, Android programming

Poem a moment Mar 2017 – Jun 2017

• An android application that shows Yoon Dongju's poems on the wallpaper

• Available on Google Play store (download 1000+)

• Skills: Android programming

TUIT Android Lecture Jun 2016 – Sep 2016

• Android development lecture provided to TUIT university students

• Skills: Android programming, Object-oriented programming

**Mr.Bill** Jun 2016 – Jul 2016

Algorithm and system to provide optimal Dutch pay way

Available on Google Play store (download 500+)

• Skills: Android programming, Graph theory

[CV compiled on 2021-04-04 for Acme Corporation]